roadtripamerica.com 2010-05-27

# About RoadTrip America®

| 

| 

RoadTrip America® is here to help you to plan your road trips and share your roadtripping passion and expertise with others. "On the road and online" since 1994, RoadTrip America offers advice, inspiration, resources, and camaraderie to all those who hear the call of the open road. RoadTrip America was founded by Megan Edwards and Mark Sedenquist. They hit the road after [their home was destroyed by wildfire](http://www.roadtripamerica.com/book/chap1.htm) in 1993, and lived on a roll for over six years. One fabulous side effect of their full-time roadtrip is that their concept of home was forever changed. As Mark puts it, "Our front yard stretches to the Gulf of Mexico, and the back goes all the way to Prudhoe Bay." That expanded view of home has contributed to RoadTrip America's governing philosophy: Wherever you travel, you're in someone's home town.  

_This is my first time here, this place is great! I, like many of the other people that I have read posts from on this site am struck with something very powerful, **wanderlust**. I am a college student and for this year's spring break I've tossed many options around. I have considered everything from skiing in Killington, VT to camping outside of Pensacola, FL. And I've finally came to the conclusion that it was time to take a road trip…_  

\-- A.B., Morgantown, WV

Today, RoadTrip America is the joint effort of editors, book reviewers, contributing writers, forum moderators, information technologists, Web designers, photographers, and hundreds of knowledgeable road trippers who generously share their discoveries, concerns, and dreams about roadtripping in North America. Members of the Great American RoadTrip Enthusiast community provide [advice and road trip planning tips](http://www.roadtripamerica.com/forum) cost-free to any registered member.

_After spending a while reading and soaking up information from this forum I've finally embarked on my first cross country road trip! I am traveling alone in my classic 1968 Chevy, the ultimate highway cruiser. So the first day I left my home on Long Island and I am headed to Yellowstone, although I plan to drive a part of Route 66, so I'll be meandering my way across the country._  

\-- D.B., Long Island, NY

We invite you to browse everything on RTA -- an amazing lineup of articles, book and product reviews, tips, and more -- like the Web's largest (and still growing) [collection of funny road signs](http://www.roadtripamerica.com/forum/content.php?128-RoadTrip-America-s-Funny-Signs-Gallery). RTA correspondents can provide road trip planning tips for solo travelers, disabled travelers, international visitors and families traveling by car, motorcycle, bicycle or RV. We are also in the process of developing a comprehensive library of road trip routes. By end of 2010, over 200 routes will be online, complete with interactive maps and plenty of up-to-the-minute tips about travel conditions, sights, and attractions. We are constantly sifting through reams of travel planning data to deliver timely and accurate information when you need and want it. For example, here's a list of [key roadside rests and attractions](http://www.roadtripamerica.com/forum/showthread.php?22915-Rest-Stops-and-Attractions-Along-all-US-Interstate-Highways) found along the major interstate highways of America.

_Having had so much help from this site I wanted to post a report of our trip and encourage others that with some planning you can have the trip of a lifetime. I started planning our trip a year in advance, my husband and I are both over 65, retired and I wasn't really convinced we could do this, until I found this Web site._  

\-- J.R. Gatwick UK

RTA is also a great source for the best road trip gear, maps, and accessories. RoadTrip America sells the best products, and every single item in our store has been vetted by a member of the RTA roadtripping community for quality, utility, and price. If you're making travel plans, RTA offers [great air, car, and hotel rates](http://travel.ian.com/index.jsp?cid=311252) in partnership with Expedia.com.

See you on the road and online!

The RoadTrip America Team

**Copyright, Media Usage and Trademarks**

A. Proprietary Rights to Content: Users, viewers and/or readers of the RoadTrip America® Web site acknowledge that all content displayed, posted and/or transmitted from the website, including but not limited to music, sound, video, graphics, data, text, multimedia, HTML, XML, and other materials collectively known as "content" may be protected by copyrights, trademarks, service marks, patents or other proprietary rights and laws. Users, viewers, and/or readers may use the content only as expressly authorized by RoadTrip America. Users, viewers, and/or readers may not copy, store, reproduce, distribute, display, publish or create derivative works from the content without express authorization from RoadTrip America.

B. Trademarks: RoadTrip America, RoadTrip Report, RoadTrip2000, Phoenix One, Earth Rover, RTA logo and all other RoadTrip America products and logos referenced herein and displayed on our Web site are trademarks, service marks or registered trademarks and registered service marks of Flattop Productions, Inc., d.b.a. RoadTrip America. Those service marks, along with those owned by third parties may not be copied, downloaded or otherwise exploited without the express permission of RoadTrip America or such third party service mark owners. Any rights not expressly granted herein are reserved.

C. Copyright Protection: RoadTrip America respects copyright law and expects all of our readers/viewers to do the same. The Internet industry depends upon copyright law to enable content providers to get fairly compensated for their content. Unauthorized copying or distribution of content is an infringement of the copyright holder's rights. RoadTrip America may elect to prosecute anyone who infringes upon the copyright, or other intellectual property rights, of RoadTrip America or any of the third parties affiliated with this website.

COPYRIGHT NOTICE. Copyright © 1996-2008 Flattop Productions, Inc. d/b/a RoadTrip America, 8275 S. Eastern Ave., Suite 200, Las Vegas, Nevada, U.S.A., All rights reserved.

D. Use of Photographs on this website: Unless a photo credit is expressly provided and/or is attached to any photograph or image found on this website, it is deemed to be the property of RoadTrip America for the exclusive use by RoadTrip America and subject to all forms of copyright protection. On occasion, RoadTrip America accepts submissions from readers/viewers of certain photographic images that are to be published in the "Funny Road Signs" or other departments within the RoadTrip America website. RoadTrip America will only accept and publish photographic images from persons who are legally authorized to grant us permission to use the images. The following information must be supplied upon submission:

1\. What is the name of the Photographer?

2\. Is the submitting person the photographer and/or do we have permission to use the photos on www.roadtripamerica.com?

3\. Where and when was the photo taken? (Please be as specific as possible with respect to the **date** and **location** of the photo.)

4\. Do we have permission to use your name, (if different from the photographer) and home city? 

5\. What is the photographer's home city/town/location?

6\. Do we have permission to extend to other publications/Websites the right to republish the images at a future date?

7\. Has your photograph been published previously on another web site?  

E. Privacy Notice: Your privacy is very important to us. Please review the privacy practices employed by RoadTrip America as explained below. 

* * *

**RoadTrip America** ® **Privacy Policy Statement**

Questions regarding the policy statement should be directed to the RoadTrip America Web site administrator for clarification at [mark@roadtripamerica.com](mailto:mark@roadtripamerica.com).

RoadTrip America believes that meeting your expectations of privacy during your visits to this Web site, is of the highest priority and is critical to the continued success of RoadTrip America and to the over-all health and vitality of the Internet. 

This privacy policy statement outlines the information practices we use, including what type of information is gathered and tracked, how this information is used and with whom any information is shared. We respect your rights and privacy and are eager to answer any questions or concerns that you may have. We can be reached at the following addresses:

E-mail: [webmaster@roadtripamerica.com  
](mailto:webmaster@roadtripamerica.com)Postal service:  
Flattop Productions, Inc./RoadTrip America  
8275 S. Eastern Avenue, Suite 200  
Las Vegas, NV 89123  
Telephone: (702)320-4866

A. Information Collected:

> 1\. In general, you can join us "on the road and online" without telling us who you are and without revealing any personal information about yourself.
> 
> 2\. We collect anonymous information from your visits to RoadTrip America by using the IP addresses from the Log files. We keep track of domain names but not the e-mail address, of anyone who visits our Web site. We use the page sharing services of both "Share This" and the RSS feed sharing by e-mail provided by "Feed Burner" and so we can view the e-mail address of both the viewer and sender of the form. These e-mail addresses are not used for any purpose except to complete the sending of the forms as requested by the site visitors.
> 
> 3\. We also collect data on some of the pages that you may visit and the information that you may submit when you use the e-mail newsletter registration form, which we call the "Guest Submission" page. We may also collect data about what you pages you looked at and/or access and how long you spent on the RoadTrip America Web site.
> 
> 4\. We may collect demographic information from the answers that you post on the registration form for the periodic RoadTrip America e-newsletter. In particular, we are interested by what sources you used when you linked to the RoadTrip America Web site the first time and whether or not you share our interest in wireless gear and services. We also solicit ideas for trip destinations or places you would like to visit along with RoadTrip America. This information is gathered for the sole reason of improving the delivery of content to you and fellow users of this Web site.
> 
> 5\. We may collect personally identifiable information from you if you elect to purchase a product or enter one of our contests or inquire about employment opportunities with RoadTrip America.
> 
> 6\. The information we collect is used for internal review and use by the editors of RoadTrip America. Unless otherwise stated, all information collected is used solely to improve the content of the Web site and services.

B. Sharing of Information:

1\. We share aggregate information with advertisers regarding the demographics of our visitors. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person.

2\. If you voluntarily provide personally identifiable information for the purpose of making a purchase or entering a contest, we will forward that specific information to the third parties for credit card/check processing and order fulfillment. While RoadTrip America will seek to require that any such third parties will follow the appropriate privacy policies and will not authorize them to use any part of this information except for the express purpose for which it was provided, RoadTrip America does not bear any responsibility for any actions or policies of any third parties.

3\. We may partner with another party to provide specific services. If you were to sign up for these special services, we will share the names and other contact information as is necessary for the third party to provide these services. Such a service could include an online personalized mapping services or a shopping service for wireless equipment. Two such services are the sharing page services referenced in paragraph A-2 and you should consult each of their privacy statements for further information about how personal information is saved on their servers.

4\. We may disclose personal identifiable information when required by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary in order to conform to the requirements of the law or to comply with legal process served on RoadTrip America.

5\. In some circumstances, usually as a result of publishing an article on RoadTrip America's Web site, we are contacted by individuals seeking personal identifiable information about a subject of the published article. We will only disclose this information to these specific third parties if we have received explicit permission from the subject of the query granting the release of this information. 

C. Links and Forums:

1\. RoadTrip America provides a multitude of links to other Web sites. Please be aware that when you click on one of these links, you will be entering another website. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of these linked Web sites as their privacy policy may differ from ours. RoadTrip America is not responsible for the privacy policies or the content of these linked Web sites.

2\. There is, at present, one forum on the RoadTrip America Web site where readers can post comments and ideas. It is known as "The Great American RoadTrip Forum." You should be aware that when you voluntarily disclose personally identifiable information, (e.g., first and last name, address, e-mail address, etc) on the forums, that information can be collected and used by others and may result in unsolicited messages from other posters or parties. If you do receive an unsolicited and UNWANTED message from anyone, please contact us as soon as possible and we will endeavor to end that person's use of the RoadTrip America's forums. In some instances, we may post the content of your e-mail messages sent to one of the principals of RoadTrip America under the appropriate forum. Further, we reserve the right to edit all postings for clarity or application on the forums.

3\. We use e-mail links within the RoadTrip America Web site to allow you to contact us directly via e-mail. We use the information provided in your e-mail to respond to your questions and comments. We may also store your comments for future reference. Your personal information is only shared with third parties with your explicit permission, with the exception of information that is posted on the forums (paragraph C.2.) referenced above.

D. On-line Advertising:

1\. RoadTrip America uses certain third party companies to deliver some banner advertisements and other on-line communication. These companies may collect and use information about the customers who clicked or viewed these banners. The information they collect is aggregated so as to protect the privacy of our readers, but RoadTrip America does not bear any responsibility for any actions or policies of any third parties.

2\. One of the online advertisers is Google.com, and Google.com as a third party vendor uses the DoubleClick DART cookie. A DART cookie is used to observe and track how a user views this site and other sites on the Internet. More information about the DART cookie system, including how to opt-out of this system [can be viewed here](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/faq.aspx). Additional information about how Google.com uses this information [may be found here](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). 

E. Cookies and other tracking technologies:

1\. RoadTrip America may use persistent "cookies" to store and track information on our Web site, enabling us to provide our visitors with customizable and personalized services. Such a service may include remembering preferences that you voluntarily set so we can supply the latest information about cutting edge wireless communication products and services. Cookies are small bits of data that we send to the browser on your computer from our Web server.

2\. RoadTrip America supports the efforts of the Platform for Privacy Preferences Project (P3P) and may incorporate some of the tracking protocol at a future date. But we feel strongly that you have the absolute authority to control any of your personal information that is gathered on this Web site. The Web site administrator will endeavor to stay current with the technological changes associated with privacy issues to ensure that your rights to privacy while visiting this Web site are protected.

F. Security:

1\. At present, RoadTrip America does not support an internal commerce Web site, (for the purchase of RTA products through the use of credit cards or electronic cash). All such purchases are conducted through third parties, and SSL encryption is used when you are prompted to enter sensitive information, (such as credit card number and/or social security number).

2\. While secure encryption technology is used to protect sensitive information on-line, we also protect all user information that is stored offline. Only one person, the Web site administrator, has access to the distribution list and database that we use to send the e-newsletters, and this person also has direct responsibility for the operation of the online forums described in paragraph C.2. 

3\. The RoadTrip America Web server is located in a locked cage in a secure facility. No unauthorized person has access of any kind to any of the RoadTrip America online files.

G. Choice/Double Opt-In:

1\. In association with Vertical Response, Inc. and FeedBurner, Inc., RoadTrip America employs a "double opt-in" registration procedure for its e-mail newsletters. Upon submission of the registration form, a reader will receive a confirmation e-mail message containing a confirmation link. Clicking on the link confirms the registration, and the reader is "double opted-in."

2\. If you have registered to receive e-mail communications from us and later change your mind, you may contact us to have your name and e-mail address removed from the distribution lists. Should you wish to remove your name and e-mail, please send an e-mail requesting removal of this information to webmaster@roadtripamerica.com.

3\. We also give you the option to remove your name and e-mail address upon receipt of every e-newsletter that we send to you.

H. Use of RoadTrip America by children:

1\. While this Web site is not directed at children, it is our intention that the content produced and published on RoadTrip America be useful, entertaining and of reasonable acceptance for all ages of children and adults. 

2\. We are supportive and committed to comply with all applicable laws and requirements in this regard.

I. Notification of Changes:

1\. This privacy statement was last updated on April 7, 2009. A notice will be posted on the RoadTrip America home page for thirty (30) days whenever this privacy statement is changed.

If you have any questions or suggestions for improvements in this privacy policy, please contact the RoadTrip America Web site administrator at [mark@roadtripamerica.com](mailto:mark@roadtripamerica.com).  
  
---
